SANDEEP KUMAR AK

+ 91-7306562205 # sandeep.akyathkambrath@gmail.com



https://www.linkedin.com/in/sandeepkumar-akyath-kambrath-70a60619/

Summary

Over all 10+ years of experience in software developing activities. Worked major projects with Samsung, Microsoft etc. Hands on experience in projects in business sectors like Social Media, Banking, Engineering, Pricing, Ecommerce and many other business projects in India/UAE. Exposure in .Net frame work, .Net core, web technologies etc.

Skill Highlights

ASP.Net, ASP.Net MVC,Core,SOAP, WCF,WEB API, Web Services SOAP, JSON, XML.Net, AngularJs CAD Soft tool (CAD.Net – CAD drawing integration in .Net Applications)

Dev Express, Dev Extreme, jQuery, jQuery Data Table.

ADO.Net, Entity framework, Linq, SQL Server 2015, 2017, PL SQL, Views, Triggers, Functions C#, VB, C, C++, JAVA, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, AJAX, jQuery,Bootstrap 3

Visual Studio Team Services, Tortoise SVN.

Experience

Senior Software Engineer Unique Hire

April 2022 – till now

- .Net back end API programmer who plan, design, implement and test API end points.
- Experienced in handling API programming for Microsoft own applications.
- Implemented changes in back end tasks in multiple sprints & deployment, load testing in Azure DevOps
- Written test cases and improved code coverage for projects having large number of functions.
- Technology highlights are ASP.Net core, Web API, MVC, C#, Entity framework, Azure Cosmos DB.

Software Engineer Timesworld India Pvt Ltd

Jan 2021 - April 2022

- Worked as senior .Net back end developer for multiple projects for Dubai government.
- Part for major projects like social media etc. for Dubai economic department DED.
- Lead developer for back end api end point projects. Responsible for team development and testing.
- Technology highlights are ASP.Net MVC, Web API, Ajax, JSON, jQuery, Bootstrap 3, CSS, HTML and SQL Server 2019, visual studio 2019.

- Working for customization and new development for web applications related to Samsung retails, shops
- Projects related to IMEI Incentive, pages and reports customization for different countries are handled.
- Worked as full stack programmer both and front end and back end business logics.
- Technology highlights are ASP.Net,Angular, Web Services for mobile apps, Ajax, JSON, jQuery, Bootstrap 3,CSS, HTML and SQL Server 2017.

Software Application Programmer SKM Air Conditioning LLC (In house software Team)

Oct 2015 - March 2020

- Worked as team lead cum developer for multipurpose business project for leading AC manufacture of Middle East.
- Handled project for automating design, pricing, bill of material calculation, ERP communication & sales order.
- Developed windows version which logically automate CAD drawings for mechanical design based on the required unit dimensions for CNC machines.
- WIN Forms, Web Forms, .Net 4.5, CAD.Net tool, Web API, JQuery, JSON, XML.Net and SQL Server 2017.

Software Support Engineer ESharp Consultancy, Dubai

2014 Feb - 2015 Sep

- Active team member as full stack programmer for developing multiple Middle East business products.
- Worked mainly for SIMS- Vehicle testing software and EBOS- Pay roll management system.
- Handled major customization for Pay role system under the communication with business development team.
- WPF/MVVM technology is used for SIMS- Vehicle testing software for Qatar based company.
- ASP.Net, Entity frame work, CSS, HTML, jQuery is used for EBos system.

Software Engineer Bearys Global InfoTech Limited, Mangalore/India

2012 Sep -2014 Jan

- Lead developer for web based e commerce web site called DigiVire (Finland).
- Project maintenance and new customizations for Admin, Supplier modules are handled by me.
- Weekly meeting with client along with manager, QA Tester for the changes and suggestions.
- Design, develop, unit test and deliver to QA.
- Once finalized by QA release to server and inform the client.
- ASP.Net core, Entity frame work, C#, SQL Server.

Software Engineer Zhikode Technologies, Kerala/India

- Team member for design, develop, and test new web project for cooperative banks in India/Kerala.
- Main task for the team to make windows version to web as well as core banking functionality
- Work closely with banking domain experts develop complete core banking applications & Reports.
- Worked for multiple pages Customer creation, Reports, Accounts, and Transactions etc.
- ASP.Net, HTML, Ajax Controls, SQL Server, Crystal Reports.

Education

Master's in computer application (MCA): Mangalore University – (2009 to 2011)

Bachelor of Science (Electronics): University of Kannur- (2004 to 2008)

Certifications

IBM Certification in Solar Eclipse - 2010

ECI Certification in Hardware and Networking - 2008

Personal Information

DOB: 20 /05/1987 – 35 years **Languages**: English, Hindi, Malayalam

Nationality: Indian Hometown: Kerala, Kannur, Payyanur

Marital status: Married (one baby girl child 4 years old) Current Location: Kannur.